Should men on TRT take NAC, Knack or an
acetylcyain?
I really like NAC and this is why Dave
probably recommended this question uh
because we have talked about that. Uh I
like it because I think it's a very
versatile supplement and there's so many
supplements out there that you know you
question well should I be taking this
for X reason? Um, and you know, if you
can only take five or six things and you
don't want to take 150 pills a day, you
kind of have to whittle down to what's
going to hit the most benefits for the
least uh least amount of resistance, I
think. So, NAC is a precursor to
glutathione, which is a master
antioxidant. It has a lot of potential
benefits in the body from the
glutathione properties. Um, specifically
for someone who's on TRT, the reason why
they might be interested in
supplementing this is for exercise
benefits. It can be beneficial for
exercise endurance, decreasing um, time
to fatigue with exercise.
Um, it's an antioxidant, so has those
benefits on the recovery pathways. Um,
also the secondary thing I would think
about would be for liver health. That's
probably the first thing I think about,
but maybe the secondary thing the
patient would think about. Um, liver
detoxification.
Um, this is an interesting supplement
because it is an over-the-counter
supplement, but is also used as a
medication for certain purposes. Um, so
NAC is used IV to um prevent liver
necrosis when someone has overdosed on
Tylenol. So that tells you how powerful
this actually can be. Um, now it's used
in really high dosing IV to do that in,
you know, kind of a one um, uh, one
infusion situation versus if you're
talking about for the fat buildup around
the liver or detoxifying from heavy
metals or other things, um, you're going
to be taking you can use an oral
supplement. Usually 600 to,200
milligrams a day is the dosing that I
would use for most cases. um 600
milligrams I think is a good just daily
dosing um for more of the preventative
or um um optimization strategies and
then you might get into that 600
milligrams twice a day if you really
have some um fatty liver or other issues
that you need to take more of. And uh
will one feel the effects? Can can you
feel the benefits? Good question. So, I
I don't think most people feel a whole
lot from taking Knack. Um, you know, if
you're taking too much, you might get
some GI distress. So, that's one way of
knowing that that um to to not push that
too hard. Um, I think that you can maybe
see more benefits on the exercise and
you would feel that and on immune
system. So, um, you know, specifically
for immune health, a lot of people will
take it as a preventative measure for
during cold and flu season. Um, it's
been shown to lessen the time that
people are down with influenza if they
do get influenza or are uh decrease the
symptoms associated with influenza. So,
that's why I personally take it is for
the immune system benefits. I started
taking it during the COVID flu period.
Yeah. Yeah. that kind of had a
resurgence at that time I think. Yeah.
Yeah. Me too. Um All right. So yeah, you
al already answered the side effect bit.
So gastrointestinal
discomfort if you take too much. Yeah.
Um and you know just kind of thinking
about those other benefits on the immune
system. You know the other thing you
could feel from it would be um using it
as a mucalytic. So if you're congested,
it can be helpful for that. And that's
another approved use that um they use a
p
uh for actual um health conditions like
cystic fibrosis um to help with clearing
the mucus. Um and I think there at one
point was a nebulized version of it for
that and for COPD as well. So again,
using it more orally as a supplement,
you could potentially see those benefits
with allergies um or other congestion
going on.
Hey,